I'm an artist and I cut books.
أنا فنان و أَقُصُّ الكتب.
This is one of my first book works.
,هذا واحد من أول أعمالي في الكتب.
It's called "Alternate Route to Knowledge."
يدعى" الطريق البديل إلى المعرفة " .
I wanted to create a stack of books so that somebody could come into the gallery
أردت صناعة مجموعة كتب ستبدو للوهلة الأولى
and think they're just looking at a regular stack of books,
ككومة عادية من الكتب،
but then as they got closer they would see this rough hole carved into it,
ولكن بعد الاقتراب سيروا أن هذا الثقب الخشن المنحوت فيها،
and wonder what was happening, wonder why,
و تتساءلون ما الذى حدث، ولماذا،
and think about the material of the book.
ويفكرون في مادة الكتاب.
So I'm interested in the texture,
لذلك أنا مهتم بالبنية،
but I'm more interested in the text and the images that we find within books.
ولكني مهتم أكثر بالنص والصور التي نجدها في الكتب.
In most of my work, what I do is I seal the edges of a book with a thick varnish
أقوم في معظم أعمالي بختم حواف الكتاب بالورنيش السميك
so it's creating sort of a skin on the outside of the book
لتشكل طبقةً على السطح الخارجي للكتاب
so it becomes a solid material, but then the pages inside are still loose,
فيصبح مادة صلبة، ولكن تبقى الصفحات في الداخل كما كانت،
and then I carve into the surface of the book,
وبعدها أبدء في نحت سطح الكتاب،
and I'm not moving or adding anything.
ولا أزيل أو أضيف أي شيء.
I'm just carving around whatever I find interesting.
أنحت فقط حول كل ما يثير اهتمامي.
So everything you see within the finished piece
لذلك كل ما ترونه داخل القطعة المنتهية
is exactly where it was in the book before I began.
ظل بالضبط في مكانه الأصلي في الكتاب قبل أن أبدأ.
I think of my work as sort of a remix, in a way,
أنا أنظر إلى عملي كنوع من إعادة المزج، بطريقة ما،
because I'm working with somebody else's material
لأنني أعمل على مادة لشخص آخر
in the same way that a D.J. might be working with somebody else's music.
بنفس الطريقة التي قد يعمل بها منسق موسيقى لموسيقى شخص آخر.
This was a book of Raphael paintings, the Renaissance artist,
كان هذا كتاب متعلق بلوحات رافاييل، فنان عصر النهضة،
and by taking his work and remixing it, carving into it,
وبأخذي لعمله وإعادتي العمل عليه بواسطة النحت فيه،
I'm sort of making it into something that's more new and more contemporary.
حولته بشكل أو بآخر إلى شيء جديد وأكثر عصرية.
I'm thinking also about breaking out of the box of the traditional book
كما أنني أفكر في الخروج من إطار الكتاب التقليدي
and pushing that linear format,
ودفع هذا الشكل الخطي،
and try to push the structure of the book itself
بل ومحاولة دفع هيكل الكتاب نفسه
so that the book can become fully sculptural.
حتى يصبح الكتاب قابل للنحت بالكامل.
I'm using clamps and ropes and all sorts of materials, weights,
وأستخدم المشابك و الحبال وجميع أنواع المواد والأوزان،
in order to hold things in place before I varnish
من أجل تثبيت الأشياء في مكانها قبل أن أضع الورنيش
so that I can push the form before I begin,
لأتمكن من تحديد الشكل قبل أن أبدأ النحت،
so that something like this can become a piece like this,
حتى يتحول شيءٍ كهذا إلى قطعةً كهذه
which is just made from a single dictionary.
مصنوعة من معجم واحد.
Or something like this can become a piece like this.
أو شيءٍ كهذا إلى قطعةً كهذه،
Or something like this,
أو شيءٌ كهذا،
which who knows what that's going to be or why that's in my studio,
لا يدري أحد ما هو سبب وجوده هذه الاعمال في الاستوديو الخاص بي،
will become a piece like this.
وكيف تتحول إلى قطعةً كهذه.
So I think one of the reasons people are disturbed by destroying books,
أعتقد أن أحد الأسباب التي تُزعج الناس في إتلاف الكتب،
people don't want to rip books
وعدم رغبتهم في تمزيقها،
and nobody really wants to throw away a book,
وأن لا أحد يريد أن يرمي كتاباً،
is that we think about books as living things,
هو أننا نعتبر الكتب بمثابة كائنات حية،
we think about them as a body,
نعتبرها كجسد،
and they're created to relate to our body, as far as scale,
وأنها خلقت نسبة لأجسادنا،
but they also have the potential to continue to grow
ولكن لديها أيضاً القدرة أن تستمر في النمو
and to continue to become new things.
وتستمر لتصبح أشياءً جديدة،
So books really are alive.
إذاً الكتب حيةٌ بالفعل.
So I think of the book as a body,
وأنا أعتبر الكتاب كجسد،
and I think of the book as a technology.
وكتقنية.
I think of the book as a tool.
وكأداة.
And I also think of the book as a machine.
وكآلة.
I also think of the book as a landscape.
وكذا كمنظرٍ طبيعي.
This is a full set of encyclopedias that's been connected and sanded together,
هذه مجموعةٌ كاملةٌ من الموسوعات وصلتها ورَمَّلْتُهَا معاً،
and as I carve through it,
خلال نحتي لها.
I'm deciding what I want to choose.
أقرر ما الذي أود أن أختاره .
So with encyclopedias, I could have chosen anything,
لذلك تتيح لي الموسوعات أن أختار أي شيء،
but I specifically chose images of landscapes.
ولكني اخترت بالتحديد صور المناظر الطبيعية.
And with the material itself, I'm using sandpaper
وبالنسبة للمادة نفسها، أستخدم ورق الصنفرة
and sanding the edges so not only the images suggest landscape,
وبصنفرة الحواف وهكذا لا تتخذ الصور وحدها شكل المنظر الطبيعي
but the material itself suggests a landscape as well.
ولكن المادة في حد ذاتها تمثل وجود منظر طبيعي أيضاً.
So one of the things I do is when I'm carving through the book,
إحدى الأشياء التي أقوم بها عند النحت في الكتاب
I'm thinking about images, but I'm also thinking about text,
ليس التفكير في الصور فحسب ، ولكن أيضاً في النص،
and I think about them in a very similar way,
و أفكر فيهما بطريقة متشابهة جداً،
because what's interesting is that when we're reading text,
لأن المثير للإهتمام هو أنه عندما نقرأ نص ما،
when we're reading a book,
عندما نقرأ كتاباً ما،
it puts images in our head,
فإنه يضع صوراً في أدمغتنا
so we're sort of filling that piece.
لذلك نحن كمن يرُصُّ تلك القطعة.
We're sort of creating images when we're reading text,
فنحن نوعاً ما نخلق صوراً عندما نقرأ نص ما،
and when we're looking at an image, we actually use language
وعندما ننظر إلى صورة ما، نقوم باستخدام اللغة
in order to understand what we're looking at.
من أجل فهم ما ننظر إليه.
So there's sort of a yin-yang that happens,
فهناك شيء يحدث كعلامة اليين واليانغ،
sort of a flip flop.
شيءٌ متقلب.
So I'm creating a piece that the viewer is completing themselves.
فأنا أصنع قطعةً يكملها المشاهد بنفسه.
And I think of my work as almost an archaeology.
وأنا أعتبر عملي شبيه بعلم الآثار.
I'm excavating and I'm trying to maximize the potential
أنا أُنَقِّب وأحاول تضخيم الإمكانيات
and discover as much as I possibly can
وأن أكتشف بقدر ما أستطيع
and exposing it within my own work.
وأظهر ذلك ضمن عملي الخاص.
But at the same time,
ولكن في الوقت نفسه،
I'm thinking about this idea of erasure,
أنا أفكر في فكرة المحو،
and what's happening now that most of our information is intangible,
وما يحدث الآن أن معظم المعلومات التي لدينا غير ملموسة،
and this idea of loss,
و فكرة الفقدان،
and this idea that not only is the format constantly shifting within computers,
وهذه الفكرة أنه ليس فقط الشكل من يتغير في الحواسيب،
but the information itself,
ولكن المعلومة نفسها،
now that we don't have a physical backup,
ولأنه ليس لدينا الآن نسخ احتياطي ملموس،
has to be constantly updated in order to not lose it.
فيجب أن تحدث باستمرار لكي لا نخسرها.
And I have several dictionaries in my own studio,
لدي العديد من المعاجم في الاستوديو الخاص بي،
and I do use a computer every day,
وأستخدم الحاسوب يومياً،
and if I need to look up a word, I'll go on the computer,
وإذا كنت بحاجة للبحث عن كلمة، سأستعمل الحاسوب،
because I can go directly and instantly to what I'm looking up.
لأنه يمكنني أن أذهب مباشرة وبسرعة لما أبحث عنه.
I think that the book was never really
أعتقد أن الكتاب لم يكن أبداً
the right format for nonlinear information,
المصدر الصحيح للحصول على المعلومات الغير خطية،
which is why we're seeing reference books
و لهذا السبب نرى أن المراجع
becoming the first to be endangered or extinct.
تصبح أول من يهددها الانقراض.
So I don't think that the book will ever really die.
أنا لا أعتقد أن الكتاب سيختفي في يوم ما.
People think that now that we have digital technology,
يعتقد الناس أنه نظراً لتوفرنا اليوم على التقنية الرقمية،
the book is going to die,
فإن الكتاب سيموت،
and we are seeing things shifting and things evolving.
ونحن نشهد اليوم على تغير الأشياء وتطورها.
I think that the book will evolve,
أعتقد أن الكتاب سيتطور،
and just like people said painting would die
وكما قال الناس من قبل أن الرسم سيموت
when photography and printmaking became everyday materials,
عندما أصبح التصوير والطباعة من الأمور اليومية،
but what it really allowed painting to do
ولكن الواقع أن ذلك جعل الرسم
was it allowed painting to quit its day job.
يخرج من رتابته.
It allowed painting to not have to have that everyday chore of telling the story,
من دوره كراوٍ للتاريخ،
and painting became free and was allowed to tell its own story,
ليتحرر فيروي قصته،
and that's when we saw Modernism emerge,
وهي لحطة ولادت الحداثة،
and we saw painting go into different branches.
وشهدنا كيف تفرع الرسم إلى فروع مختلفة.
And I think that's what's happening with books now,
وأعتقد أن هذا ما يحدث مع الكتب الآن،
now that most of our technology, most of our information,
مع تحول معظم تقنيتنا ومعلوماتنا
most of our personal and cultural records are in digital form,
ومعظم سجلاتنا الشخصية والثقافية لتصبح رقمية،
I think it's really allowing the book to become something new.
أصبح بمقدور الكتاب ان يتحول لشيء جديد.
So I think it's a very exciting time for an artist like me,
لذلك أعتقد أنها فترة مثيرة للغاية لفنان مثلي،
and it's very exciting to see what will happen with the book in the future.
أن يراقب ما سيؤول إليه الكتاب مستقبلاً.
Thank you.
شكراً
(Applause)
(تصفيق)